Bart de Goede | Resume

San Francisco CA, United States

☑://bart@degoe.de in://bart-de-goede ۞://bartdegoede https://bart.degoe.de

Summary

I am a senior full-stack software engineer with more than 9 years experience. I co-founded a web development agency, worked as a senior software engineer on the search and data teams of one of the fastest growing unicorns in Europe, on the search and then web foundations team at a digital library, e-book and audiobook subscription service, and am currently part of the growth team at a grocery delivery service. I love building scalable systems, designing sensible APIs, working on products that users can't live without, helping others succeed, and explaining complicated things in a way everyone can understand.

Skills

Natural languages English (fluent), Dutch (native)

Programming languages Python, Ruby, SQL, Javascript, Go, Scala

Frameworks Django, Flask, Rails, Grape, D3, React

Databases MySQL, PostgreSQL, Elasticsearch, Solr, MongoDB, Redis

Tools and versioning Git, Mercurial, Virtualbox, Vagrant, Ansible, Fabric, Chef, AWS, Terraform

Other keywords Agile software development (Scrum, Kanban), user-focused, AB-testing, Nginx, ELK, Resque, Grafana, Datadog, (micro)services, architecture, (RESTful) API design, experience with several libraries for machine learning, information retrieval, recommendations and natural language processing (NLTK, Gensim, scikit-learn), Spark, Airflow, Scrapy, Linux (server) environments, bash scripting, Unicorn, uWSGI, RabbitMQ, AngularJS, BackboneJS, jQuery, Kafka, markup languages such as HTML, XML and CSS

Experience

Instacart

Senior Software Engineer II, Growth

October 2021 - Present

Role: Senior software engineer on the Growth team, sending 75+ million relevant messages to our users. This includes emails, push notifications and in-app merchandising.

Skills used: Ruby, Python, RSpec, Airflow, (Postgre)SQL, Redis, Memcached, React/Javascript, Braze

Scribd

Senior Software Engineer, Search and Web Infrastructure

October 2018 - October 2021

Role: Senior software engineer on the search and web infrastructure teams, making sure our 250 million monthly users can find the content they're looking for in Scribd's vast catalog. This includes developing search and ranking features, as well as being the team subject matter expert for Elasticsearch.

Interesting challenges: Migrated Elasticsearch and search applications to AWS in less than 6 months. This increased the resiliency, reliability and scalability of the Elasticsearch clusters, reduced downtime risks, and unlocked testing different analysis pipelines and relevance tuning experiments at scale. Rebuilt controller and frontend architecture for content preview pages in 8 weeks, allowing for rollout of other content types in 2 days, while improving core web vital metrics.

 $\textit{Skills used:} \ \ \text{Ruby, Python, RSpec, Elasticsearch, (My)SQL, Redis, Spark, Chef, Go, Terraform, React/Javascript}$

Catawiki

Senior Software Engineer, Search & Discovery and Data Science teams

February 2016 - September 2018

Role: Senior developer responsible for site search, auction and category pages, and the integration of data science models with the Catawiki platform. This includes technical responsibilities for ETL, query building and performance optimization, product responsibilities such as integrating business requirements with search rankings and team responsibilities such as cross-team mentoring, pair programming and code reviews.

Interesting challenges: Migrated the site search from the legacy monolith application with Solr to a separate microservice using Elasticsearch. The migration was required to have no downtime, and have no negative impact on the business; resulted in increase of 47% in visitor-to-bidder ratio in sessions using search.

Company activities: Chief editor for engineering content and board member of The Catawikian, the internal magazine. Skills used: Ruby, RSpec, Grape, Elasticsearch, Solr, MySQL, Redis, Python, Ansible, ELK

Dispectu

Co-founder

September 2012 - November 2015

Dispectu was a full-stack software development agency that specialized in web applications, search engine implementations and data visualization. We built search engines and interactive data visualization applications for a variety of customers. Examples include building an open source API for publicly available cultural open data, an ngram-viewer for 150 years worth of OCR-ed Dutch newspapers and natural language processing APIs.

University of Amsterdam

Research assistant 2010–2012

Role: Developing software for the PoliticalMashup research project, where we built a database of Dutch political data (parliamentary proceedings, biographical data, laws, etcetera).

Skills used: Python, eXist-db, XML, Xpath, Solr

Additional activities

Elasticsearch core training 2014
E&Y NextGen Academy 2011

Education

University of Amsterdam

Master of Information Science 2011–2012

Thesis: Sustainable Questions

Thesis published at SIGIR 2012 Workshop on Time-aware Information Access

University of Amsterdam

Bachelor of Information Science 2008–2011

Thesis: Political slant in Dutch public broadcasting

Student member of the Department Committee

2008-2011

The Department Committee is responsible for safeguarding and advising the department board and dean on the quality of teaching, organisation and the course curriculum.

Attended ESSIR in Koblenz (European Summer School in Information Retrieval)

2011

Publications

- **2013** Huurnink, B., Bronner, A., Bron, M., Van Gorp, J., de Goede, B. & van Wees, J. AVResearcher: Exploring Audiovisual Metadata. In *CEUR Workshop Proceedings* (2013), vol. 986, pages 1–2.
- 2013 De Goede, B., van Wees, J., & Marx, M. Politicalmashup ngramviewer. In *Proceedings of the 13th Dutch-Belgian Workshop on Information Retrieval* (April 2013), vol. 986, pages 54–55. Winner of the conference *Best demonstrator award*.
- **2012** Migut, M., van Wees, J., Bakker, D., de Goede, B., Steltenpohl, H., Oude Lenferink, N., & Worring, M.. VAST challenge 2012: Interactively finding anomalies in geo-temporal multivariate data. In *Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Visual Analytics Science and Technology*, Seattle, WA, October 2012.
- **2012** Goede, B. de, Schuth, A. & Rijke, M. de (2012). Sustainable Questions: Determining the Expiration Date of Answers. In *SIGIR 2012 Workshop on Time-aware Information Access: #TAIA2012*, Portland, OR, August 2012. Accepted papers. Microsoft Research.
- **2011** De Goede, B., Marx, M., Nusselder, A., & van Wees, J. (2011). Succinct summaries of narrative events using social networks. In *Proceedings of the 22nd ACM conference on Hypertext and hypermedia*, pages 299–304.